Hello everyone and
welcome back to English Pod.
My name is Marco and my
name is Catherine and today
we're talking about one of
my least favorite things Marco.
Mosquitoes. Mosquitoes.
They're all over the place
especially in summer or
near water and for me the
worst part is when you
are trying to sleep and
there's a mosquito that
just keeps on biting you
and won't let you sleep.
You can kind of hear it
around your head
you know by your ears.
I hate that or when you just
get bitten and you're in bed
and it's just so much
you can't burn sometimes.
Yeah so that's what we're
talking about today fun stuff.
Let's jump right
into this dialogue
and we'll be back in a
minute to talk about what's
going on. The mosquitoes
are biting me. Me too.
I can't stop scratching. They're
everywhere sneaky little jerks.
Do you have any bug spray?
No I forgot to buy some.
Then we'll have to put up with it.
We can cover
ourselves with beer.
That way if they bite us
they'll get drunk and fall asleep.
That's without doubt.
The best idea you've ever had. Let's do it.
Run! They're thirsty for more!
All right we're back
so let's take a look
at some of these words
in language takeaway.
Language takeaway. All
right so as we mentioned
we're going to be
talking about mosquitoes
and well these are just
little small insects that
suck your blood. They
do and they're very thin
and I'm not much to say
about them they were very
important in the movie Jurassic
Park if you remember that.
Right now what's the
difference between a
mosquito and a fly? Okay
a fly usually is just annoying.
It doesn't suck your
blood but a mosquito does.
It sucks your blood and flies are fatter
and like shorter and they're big and
black or green kind of
something. Black and green
and they yeah they just
buzz around and mosquitoes
actually bite you. Okay
so a mosquito and a fly.
Now if a mosquito
bites you you really really
want to scratch. That's
right so you feel like you
need to scratch your
body because you have this
bite you know it's really
an allergy and you have a
red bump on your arm a
red mark and you scratch
and it gets worse and
worse. All right and moving
on to our next word
mosquitoes have a reputation
of being sneaky. Okay so
you can say sneaky about
a lot of things one you
know obviously we're
saying mosquitoes are
very sneaky. That means that
they can kind of hide and get
you when you're not expecting it.
Yeah because sometimes during the day you
don't really see them in your room right
they're hiding or they're
in a place where you can
really see them and then at
night all of a sudden they come out.
They come out. So and
they're very hard to see.
They fly around in in a way that's very
difficult to catch them or kill them right.
Right we could say
thieves are very sneaky.
Like a thief is someone
who steals something
and they like to sneak
around and hide in the
dark and then when you're not expecting
it they come out and they steal your stuff.
Exactly and now what do we
what do we do or what do we use
in order to prevent
mosquitoes from biting us?
This is essential
especially if you're going to
the beach we bring
bug spray. Bug spray.
So a spray is something
that that you can usually have
in a can that you push a
button then it comes out.
Right it's like it's like water
but it keeps the bugs away.
So bug spray keeps bugs away not only
mosquitoes but like flies to flies or any other
type of bug. Now specifically
from mosquitoes you
would use maybe a
mosquito repellent.
Right so repellent is it means
something that pushes or
keeps away things you
don't want. So something that
keeps mosquitoes away is
called a mosquito repellent.
Usually it's a cream you
put on your arms or legs.
All right very good.
So interesting words
that we've just taken
a look at. Let's listen to
our dialogue again
and we'll be right back.
The mosquitoes are
biting me. Me too.
I can't stop scratching. They're
everywhere sneaky little jerks.
Do you have any bugs spray?
No I forgot to buy some.
Then we'll have to put up with it.
We can cover ourselves
with beer. That way if
they bite us they'll get
drunk and fall asleep.
That's without doubt. The
best idea you've ever had
let's do it. Run.
They're thirsty for more.
All right we're back so
now let's take a look at
a couple of different
phrases on fluency builder.
Fluency builder. All
right so the first phrase is
very very common. The
person in the dialogue says
that they're going to
have to put up with it.
Put up with these
mosquitoes because they didn't
have any bug spray.
So this phrase to put up
with is really important.
All right so if you put
up with something and
these that you tolerate it.
All right that means even
if you don't want to you'll
still handle it. You'll still
have to deal with that.
You accept it. So
maybe you have a little
brother that's very annoying and
you just have to put up with him.
There's no other
option. Yeah or someone
says to you you're just
going to have to put up
with it or you say I won't
put up with it anymore.
I won't handle it
anymore. I'm done.
All right so I think this
is a great phrase for us to
take a look at a couple
of different examples.
Example one. I can't put up with the
noise any longer. Turn that music down.
Example two. If you
can put up with the smell
then stinky tofu is
actually very tasty.
Example three. I've had to put up with
him for too long. I want a new roommate.
We've got another phrase.
We're talking about beer.
Okay and so the person
says oh I have an idea.
Instead of bug spray
we can we can cover
ourselves with beer.
So to cover yourself or
cover ourselves. So it means that we put it
all over us. Right so you could even cover
yourself with bug spray.
Okay so every part of
your body you put bug
spray on. Head to toe.
Head to toe. Now you
can cover yourself under a
tree maybe or you can
cover yourself with a blanket.
Okay so to cover
yourself to completely hide
under something. And
finally we have the response
to this idea, the answer.
The person says oh
without a doubt that means
absolutely or definitely.
Okay so there is no doubt.
It is true or it is certain.
Right so a doubt is something
that maybe you're not so sure about.
You're not convinced. But you
can say this is without a doubt
the best mosquito spray.
Or this is without a doubt
the best cake I've ever
eaten. That means it's
definitely the best
cake I've ever eaten.
All right so I think we've
covered all the phrases now.
Why don't we listen to our dialogue
for the last time and we'll be right back.
The mosquitoes are
biting me. Me too.
I can't stop scratching. Here
everywhere sneaky little jerks.
Do you have any bug spray?
No I forgot to buy some.
Then we'll have
to put up with it.
We can cover
ourselves with beer.
That way if they bite us
they'll get drunk and fall asleep.
That's without doubt.
The best idea you've ever had. Let's do it.
Run! They're thirsty for more.
The mosquitoes are very
annoying but at times they
can be very dangerous
right? They can.
There are a couple of diseases
that can be passed by mosquito bites.
One of them is
malaria and that's I think
pretty common in
Southeast Asia and South Asia.
Now there was another
situation where people believe
that if a mosquito bit a
person infected with HIV
or AIDS they could pass
it on to another person.
Aha well I don't know that
that's even possible because
there's no AIDS-carrying
mosquitoes but there's another
disease called dengue
fever. Dengue fever yeah
and this is another
very dangerous one.
It's also known as break
bone fever and I think it's it's
so painful it feels like
your bones are breaking
and that's when the
game comes back.
It's very common in South
America as well and because we have
such a tropical climate
that in the rainforest of
Brazil, Peru, Colombia
it's common to see this but
not so much any more
another eradicating it.
All right so an interesting
topic mosquitoes are not
only irritating but
can be dangerous.
So if you have any other
questions or doubts please come to
our website englishpot.com and
we're there to answer any questions.
So we'll see you on the website
and until next time everyone bye bye. Bye!